Elijah Raffo

Portland, OR 97224

- (971) 275-7057
- eliraffo@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/eliraffo
- eliraffo.github.io

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

A business and data analyst with a passion for utilizing information to create and implement impactful solutions. Completed projects in optimization, database design, automation, machine learning, cost assessment, and improving functional areas. Has experienced working within a fast-paced environment, building a team, learning complex business systems, communicating nuanced concepts, problem solving, and being a self-starter.

EDUCATION

University of Oregon ● Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

Major Concentration • Operations and Business Analytics

Minor

■ Computer Information Technology

Relevant Coursework: Supply Chain Operations and Management • Business Strategy and Planning • Predictive Analytics • Database Systems

WORK EXPERIENCE

Operations Analyst (Part-time)

Lane Forest Products, Inc. ● Eugene, OR

June 2018 - Current

Sept. 2015 - June 2019

GPA: 3.60 / 4.0

General Responsibilities:

<u>Performed</u> database queries, data analysis, and data visualization to answer varying stakeholder questions about business operations.

Reported weekly on material sent to a wood pellet producer to inform managerial delivery schedule.

<u>Improved</u> multiple functional areas by redesigning spreadsheets thereby decreasing future spreadsheet maintenance and improving efficiency.

Worked with the Offsite Production Supervisor to reimagine monthly reporting, contract generation, and offsite scheduling.

Operated as the inventory control specialist of a logistic reload which over 6 months which moved over 55,000 tons of material.

Partnered with the database manager to automate an extract, transform, and load process.

Operated as the export specialist for international orders by managing documentation, accounts payable/receivable, and movement of materials.

Created Project flowcharts and procedures to simplify and scale the international export of material.

Analytic Projects:

Intermediate

<u>Conducted</u> an analysis of the Delivery Department by quantitatively measuring costs and modeling possible profit/loss combinations which resulted in a proposed pricing structure that is estimated to increase department annual profit by \$36,000.

Created visual models for stakeholders which intuitively explained the profit margin of all order combinations (~50,000 combinations)

Supply Logistics Intern

Townshend's Tea Company ● Portland, OR

June 2017 – September 2017

<u>Implemented</u> a redesigned Point-of-Sale interface at all Eugene Teahouse locations which resulted in:

- Data that can measure Key Performance Indicators and be used in a Material Resource Planning system.
- A spreadsheet that Storefront managers could use to automate bi-weekly inventory counting and reorder points.

SKILLS

Beginner * R ● * VBA | Macros ● Google Analytics ● Demand Forecasting ● Regression ● Database Modeling ● React.js

* Excel ● * Tableau ● * SQL ● * Python ● Optimization ● JavaScript ● MS Office | Visio, Access, Outlook

PROJECTS AND CERTIFICATES

Wine Using python, developed machine learning models to classify and predict the quality of a wine (up to an 85% accuracy). Presented on the findings and impact these models could have on the industrial wine making process.

Hershey's Built an optimization model which factors in the inventory and production constraints to produce a Hershey's Kiss. Reported the Optimization optimized four-week production cycle where weekly supply, demand, and carry-over inventory constraints fluctuate.

Video GameRecorded data on video game accessories, consoles, and games. Produced an ER diagram, relational schema, and databaseDatabasebuilt to the second normal form. Presented on queries that answer real world consumer questions.

Certificate of Over 3 years, attended classes on developing leadership skills and survival skills in the backcountry. Applied these lessons as an assistant leader in university classes taught by the Outdoor Pursuits Program. Experienced leading groups of six on three-day backcountry outings, teaching outdoor rock-climbing safety, and teaching vertical rescue techniques.

^{*} Improved further outside of University by enrolling in online courses or through work